Guide to the Kent Family Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II. Legal Opinions, Notes, and Correspondence Regarding Issues of the Law, 1791-1851 and undated
  - From the Board of Trustees of Vincennes University to the General Assembly of Indiana with corresponding Act of Incorporation document, 1843 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Legal opinion on the case of Vincennes University with letter from Vincennes University to James Kent, James Kent, December 4 & 15, 1843 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Legal opinion on Follain, Bellocq, and Degelos vs. Jacques Dupre, James Kent, September 5, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Legal opinion on Richard Townings will with related letter from Charles Edwards, James Kent, December 26 & 30, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Legal opinion on W.S. Wetmore vs. William Lejee & William Cooper, James Kent, May 5, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Legal opinion of the court in Union Bank of Tennessee vs. Solomon D. Jacobs and related letter from Jacobs to James Kent, James Kent and Supreme Court of Tennessee, September and December 1845 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Legal opinion in Merchant of Apalachiola Florida vs. the city charter, James Kent, 1845. (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Notes on "Duer's Lecture…on the branch of Neutrality," James Kent, October 15, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Legal opinion on the Apalachiola Florida inspection laws with related letter from A. Robertson Rogers, James Kent, February 5 & 9, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Legal opinion on the duties of Trustees, William Curtis Noyes, in the hand of James Kent, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Notes on "Admissibility of paid evidence," William Kent, February 20, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Legal opinion on the case of the Brooklyn and Gowannus Toll Bridge Co., James Kent, February25 1847 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Notes on usage in law, William Kent, March7, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Notes on duties of nations in peace, William Kent, March 9,1847 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Notes on Reprisals, William Kent, March 12, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Notes on trading with the enemy,William Kent, March 15, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Notes on armed neutrality, William Kent, March 15, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Notes on contraband of war, William Kent, March 21, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - legal opinion on the mortgage of a railroad, William Kent, December 2, 1847 (Box 2)
  - Legal opinion on the mortgage of a railroad, William Kent, December 2, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - (Draft) legal opinion on the rights of proprietors to redeemed land, William Kent, February 16, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Official legal opinion on the rights of proprietors to redeemed land, William Kent, February 29, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Agreement on the construction of a railroad under the title "Company of Panama" and related terms of business, signed by Winfield Scott, William Kent, and others. December 11, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Report on Committees of Examination, Harvard University Board of overseers and William Kent, March 20, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Legal opinion on the case of Phoenix vs. Whitney, William Kent, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Legal opinion on the case of Isaachinsssen vs. Newport Fire & Marine Insurance Co., William Kent, July 29, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Legal opinion on the case of Mark Anthony D'Wolf vs James D'Wolf, Jr., James Kent, undated (presumably in the late 1830s or early 1840s) (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Legal opinion on Schuyler vs. Williams, James Kent, undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Legal opinion on the case of the murder of Samuel Adams by John C. Colt, William Kent, undated but presumably from 1842. (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Legal opinion on the Bankrupt Act of 1841 William Kent, undated (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Notes on Bankrupcy, William Kent, undated (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Notes on "Smith's Leading Cases, Wigglesworth vs. Dallison,"William Kent, undated (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Notes on contracts, William Kent, 1847 and undated (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Notes on promissory notes, William Kent, undated (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Notes on the Restraining Act of 1804 William Kent, undated (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Notes on the "Construction of the Constitution," William Kent, undated (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Miscellaneous legal papers and briefs, William Kent, undated (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Legal opinion on a case of Trust, William Kent, undated (Box 2, Folder 82)
- Series III. Legal Documents and Other Items, 1820-1901 and undated
  This series contains diplomas, certificates to practice, certificates of membership, wills, executor documents, copyrights, and various memorabilia collected by the Kent family such as calling cards, stamps, clippings, engravings, currency, silhouettes, and many autographs of the Revolutionary period. This series is divided into 9 sub-series and arranged chronologically. There are 68 folders.
  - Sub-Series III.1: Diploma
    - Diploma from Union College, William Kent, July 26, 1820 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sub-Series III.2: Certificates to Practice
    - Certificate to practice law before the New York Supreme Court, William Kent, Feb 27, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Certificate to practice as councellor before the Supreme court of New York, William Kent, October27 1826 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Certificate to practice before the Chancery Court of New York, William Kent, March13 1826 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Appointment as Commissioner of Deeds and Notary, William Kent, April 23,1827 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Certificate to practice as Judge Advocate for the 10th Brigade, William Kent, May 25,1827 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Appointment as Judge Advocate for the 10th Brigade, William Kent, July 19,1827 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Certificate of admission to practice as councilor for the Chancery Court of New York, William Kent, May 27,1828 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Certificate of Admission to Practice Law, James Kent, Jr., February26,1852 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Certificate of Admission to practice law before the Southern District of New York, James Kent, Jr., May 20, 1854 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Sub-Series III.3: Certificates of Membership
    - Certificate of membership in the Jefferson County Society for Promoting Agriculture and Domestic Manufactures, James Kent, March1, 1819. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Certificate of membership in the Albany County Society for Promoting Agriculture and Domestic Manufactures, James Kent, October11,1819 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Certificate of membership in the United Domestic Missionary Society, May 1, 1826 James Kent (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Certificate of membership in the American Philosophical Society, James Kent, April 17,1829 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Certificate of membership in the Peithologian Society of Columbia College, William Stewart, October7, 1842 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Sub-Series III.4: Copyrights, Affadavits and Insurance regarding Commentaries on American Law by James Kent
    - Copyright for "Commentaries" signed by Henry Clay, December8, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Copyright for "Commentaries" vol. 2 signed by Henry Clay, January9,1828 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Copyright for Commentaries vol. 3 signed by Henry Clay, January25,1829 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Affadavits of the public notices of James Kent's application for copyright for Commentaries, 1826-1830 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Copyright for Commentaries vol. 4, signed by Martin Van Buren, June 30,1830 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Copyright for Commentaries vol.2 and 4, 2nd edition, with memorandum. August21,1832 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Copyright for Commentaries vol.1-4, 4th edition, February22 1841 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Copyright for Commentaries, May 1844 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Insurance policy on William Kent's edition of James Kent's "Commentaries" from the Lefarge Fire Insurance Co., June 12, 1854 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Sub-Series III.5: Property Deeds and Agreements
    - Auditors deed to John Fleming, Illionois Auditor of Public Accounts, April 7,1830 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Property deed to John and Phebe Blackburn to James Kent, March22 1845 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Property deed to John and Phebe Blackburn to James Kent, May 15,1845 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Property deed from Nicholas Dean to William Kent, June 25,1849 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - property deed from Thomas Adis Emmet to William Kent, June 29,1849 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Property deed from Thomas Adis Emmet to William Kent, June 1849 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Sub-Series III.6: Resignations and Dissolutions
    - Acceptance of his resignation as the Judge Advocate of the 10th Brigade, William Kent, October17 1831 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Dissolution of the partnership of William Kent and William Samuel Johnson, September 6, 1841 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Sub-Series III.7: Kent Family Wills, Executor Documents, and Estate Inventories
    - Early will of James Kent cancelled by a later will, September 11,1841 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Codicil to James Kent will of Sept,.11,1841 February 9, 1844 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Final Will of James Kent and related Probate of Will, August 22, 1846 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Letters testamentary appointing William Kent as executor of the estate of James Kent, December 24, 1847 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Notice of inventory of the estate of James Kent, affidavit of service of the inventory, and note added to the affidavit, January 5, 7, and 15, 1848 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Account of the estate of James Kent, 1861-1863 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Appointment of William Kent as executor of the estate of Moss Kent, in lieu of James Kent, June 1, 1848 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - The will of William Kent recorded by Peter Doilaine, surrogate, originally created June 8, 1849 recorded January 15, 1861 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - The will of Abigail I. Riggs, 1855-1861 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Sub-Series III.8: Kent Family Resolutions
    - Resolutions on the death of James Kent, New York Law Association, December 13, 1847 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Resolutions on the Death of James Kent, New York Bar Association, December 14, 1847 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Resolution on the death of James Kent, New York Historical Society, December 14, 1847 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Resolution on the death of James Kent, New York Historical Society, December 1847 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Remarks of Mr. Godwin on the death of James Kent, December 1847 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - resolution of the bar association of texas on the death of james kent with related letter to william kent from jonas butler, January 3 and 14, 1848 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Resolution on the death of James Kent, New Jersey Bar Association, January 8, 1848 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Resolutions on the death of James Kent, Detroit Bar Association, January 4, 1848 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Sub-Series III.9: Miscellaneous
    - Customs Certificate for the importation of wine, New York Port Authority, July 27, 1794 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Military Pass issued to James Kent Jr., signed by James Kent Jr. and Drake De Kay, July 4, 1861 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Recipes in the hand of James Kent, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Table of contents from the original bound scrapbook of the Kent manuscripts, unsigned and undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Currency and postage stamps, 5 items, 1861-1901 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1831, 1843, 1852, 1854, 1876, 1879, 1881 and 1892 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Autographs of the Revolutionary period, 24 items (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Map of the land about Gramercy Park belonging to Samuel B. Ruggles to be sold at auction, December 1833 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Ticket of admission to an assembly at Haberdashers Hall issues to William (?) Pinckney from Thomas Raikes, March 28, 1799 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Prospectus of the Morse Geneaology, Abner Morse, July 1, 1848 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Bank checks made out to and endorsed by William Kent, January 1854 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Package express receipts from the Adams & Co. Express, James Kent, September 1845 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Engraved portrait of Thomas Hamilton, printed by Illman and Pilbrow, undated (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Kent Family Tree from the descent of John Moss to William Kent II, undated (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Kent family crest impression in sealing wax, undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Engraved portrait of Edward Law (Lord Ellenborough), undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Chinese Water Colors and silhouettes of James Kent and others, 1833 and undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Circular, membership, rules and schedule of the Kent Club, undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Membership list and notes on the Union Club of New York, 1838 and 1901 (Box 3, Folder 68)
- Series IV. Journals and Catalogs, 1797-1847
  This series contains the journals and library catalog of James Kent and John Seely Stone. There are 9 Items, arranged chronologically.
  - "Memoir of a Journey I made from New York to the Eastern States," James Kent, August 9, 1797 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Journal of the Napoleonic Campaigns of 1807 and 1808 and sketch of Germany, James Kent, sketch created in 1780 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Journal of the Napoleonic Campaigns of 1809-1812 James Kent (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Journal of a European Tour, John Seely Stone, 1826 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Journal of a European Tour, unknown author, 1826 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Catalog of James Kent's Library, 1842 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Diary of James Kent, 1839, 1842-1843 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Diary of James Kent, 1842-1847 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Diary of James Kent, 1847 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Series V. Lecture Notes and Reading Notes, 1783-1860 and undated
  This series is comprised of notes and transcriptions of various authors, philosophers, and scholars taken predominantly by James Kent and William Kent. It is divided into 5 sub-series that vary in arrangement (organized alphabetically by author or topic). There are 78 folders in this series.
  - Sub-Series V.1: Notes on the works of published single authors
    - Blackstone, W., & Stewart, J. (1839). The rights of persons: According to the text of Blackstone: incorporating the alterations down to the present time. London: E. Spettigue., in the hand of William Kent, 1846 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Belknap, J. (1791). The History of New Hampshire... by Jeremy Belknap. Boston: the author. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Bynkershoek, C.. (1674). Probabilium juris civilis liber 1. Lugd[uni] Batavorum: Drucker:] Lopez., in the hand of James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Catteau-Calleville, J. -P. (1790). A general view of Sweden: Containing, besides a geographical description of the country, an account of its constitution, religion, .... Together with the manners and customs of its inhabitants, ... Translated from the French of Mr. Catteau. London: printed for G. G. J. and J. Robinson., in the hand of James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Notes from "Cicero volume 2", in the hand of James Kent, 1795 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Notes on Cicero's De Natura Deorum, in the hand of James Kent, 1801 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Chesterfield, P. D. S., Stanhope, P., & Readex. (1775). Letters written by the late Right Honourable Phillip Dormer Stanhope, Earl of Chesterfield, to his son, Philip Stanhope, Esq; late envoy extraordinary at the Court of Dresden: Together with several other pieces on various subjects.: Published by Mrs. Eugenia Stanhope, from the originals now in her possession.: In four volumes.: Vol. I[-IV]. New York: London, printed: New-York, re-printed by J. Rivington and H. Gaine., in the hand of James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Colquhoun, P. (1796). A treatise on the police of the metropolis: Containing a detail of the various crimes and misdemeanors by which public and private property and security are, at present, injured and endangered: and suggesting remedies for their prevention. The third edition, revised and enlarged., By a magistrate. London: printed by H. Fry, for C. Dilly., in the hand of James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Coke, E. (1642). The second part of the Institutes of the lawes of England: Containing the exposition of many ancient, and other statutes: whereof you may see the particulars in a table following. London: Printed by M. Flesher, and R. Young, for E.D., R.M., W.L., and D.P., in the hand of James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Dalrymple, J. (1758). An essay towards a general history of feudal property in Great Britain: Under the following heads, I. History of the introduction of the feudal system into Great-Britain: II. History of tenures: III. History of the alienation of land property: IV. History of entails: V. History of the laws of succession or descent: VI. History of the forms of conveyance: VII. History of jurisdictions, and the forms of procedure in courts: III. History of the constitution of Parliament. London: Printed for A. Millar., in the hand of James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Darwin, E. (1789). The botanic garden: A poem, in two parts: with philosophical notes. London: printed for J. Johnson., in the hand of James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Eggestein, H (1472) Libri feudorum. Strassburg, in the hand of James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Fleury, C., In Beaver, J., & Argou, G. (1724). The history of the origine of the French laws: Translated from the French. London: Printed for D. Browne and Clay, in the hand of James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Frederick,. (1787). The art of war: A poem in six books. Tr. from the French of the King of Prussia. London: s.n.., from the Critical Review in the hand of James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Notes on the characters of Herodotus from Gillies, J. (1790). The History of Ancient Greece, Its Colonies, and Conquests, from the earliest accounts till the division of the Macedonian empire in the East: Including the history of literature, philosophy, and the fine arts. Basil., in the hand of James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Godwin, W. (1793). Enquiry concerning political justice and its influence on morals and happiness: 1. London: Robinson., in the hand of James Kent, 1796 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Polybius, ., & Hampton, James (1772). The general history of Polybius: In five books. London: Printed by H.S. Woodfall for J. Dodsley., unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - "Notes on Washington Irving's works from an English Review," unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Lambardus,. (1568). Archaionomia., in the hand of James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Le, C. G. L., & Smellie, W. (1785). Natural history, general and particular, by the Count de Buffon, Translated into English. Illustrated with above 300 copper-plates, and occasional notes and observations, by William Smellie. London: W. Strahan & T. Cadell., unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Notes "On Philosophy and Logic extracted from a jumble of matter heaped together at college" includes notes on mineral and natural philosophy from John Locke (1632 – 28 October 1704)., unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Notes on the works of Machiavelli, unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Mathias, T. J. (1798). The pursuits of literature: A satirical poem in four dialogues: with notes. Dublin: Printed by P. Byrne., unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Necker, J. (1791). Historical review of the administration of Mr. Necker: Written by himselTranslated from the French. London: printed for G. G. J. and J. Robinson., unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Paley, W. (1796). Horæ Paulinæ: Or, the truth of the scripture history of St. Paul evinced. .... By William Paley. London: printed for R. Faulder., written in the hand of William Kent, 1847 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Pennant, T. (1792). Introduction to the Arctic zoology. London: Printed for Robert Faulder., unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Priestley, J. (1788). Lectures on history and general policy; to which is prefixed an essay on a course of liberal education for civil and active life, unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Notes on Institutio Oratoria by Marcus Fabius Quintilianus (ca. 35 – ca. 100), unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Notes from the works of Guillaume Thomas Raynal (1713 –1796), unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Reeves, J. (1863). Reeves' History of the english law from the time of the Romans to the end of the reign of Elizabeth. London: Reeves and Turner, unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Transcription of David Rittenhouse "An Oration on Astronomy (1783), unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Roscoe, W. (1822). Illustrations, historical and critical, of the life of Lorenzo de' Medici, called the Magnificent: Illustrations. London: Printed for T. Cadell, ... and W. Blackwood, Edinburgh., unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Russell, W. (1802). The history of modern Europe: With an account of the decline and fall of the Roman empire: and a view of the progress of society, from the rise of the modern kingdoms to the peace of Paris, in 1763. Philadelphia: Printed for William Young Birch and Abraham Small (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - And notes from the writings of James Beattie (1735-1803)., unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5)
    - Salmon, J. (1798). A description of the works of art of ancient and modern Rome: Particularly in architecture, sculpture & painting. To which is added, a tour through the cities and towns in the environs of that metropolis. .... By J. Salmon. London: printed for the author, by J. Sammells, unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Savary, ., Le, M., Williams, J., G. G. J. and J. Robinson (Paternoster-Row, London, England),, New York Society Library., New York Society Library., & New York Society Library. (1788). Letters on Greece: Being a sequel to Letters on Egypt, and containing travels through Rhodes, Crete, and other islands of the Archipelago; with comparative remarks on their Ancient and present State, and observations on the Government, Character, and Manners, of the Turks, and Modern Greeks. London: Printed for G. G. J. and J. Robinson, Paternoster-Row., unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Savigny, M. C. D. (1855). Traite De Droit Romain. Paris: Firmin Didit Freres., in the hand of William Kent, 1847 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Translations of sections of Savigny, Traite De Droit Romain in the hand of William Kent, 1847 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Notes from the works of Charles-Louis de Secondat, Baron de Montesquieu (1689-1755), unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Notes on Emperor Antoninus taken from the works of John Selden (1584-1654), in the hand of William Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Sherlock, M., & Duncombe, J. (1780). Letters from an English traveller [Martin Sherlock, esq.]. London: Printed for J. Nichols; T. Cadell; H. Payne; and N. Conant., unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Miscellaneous notes on the works of Thomas Spence (1750 –1814), unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Notes from Thomas Spence on the construction of contracts, William Kent, 1846 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - . Stewart, J. (1796). An inquiry into the principles of political economy being an essai on the science of domestic policy in free nations. Basil., unknown transcriber, undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Temple, W. (1673). Observations upon the United Provinces of the Netherlands. London: Printed by A. Maxwell for Sa. Gellibrand., in the hand of James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Notes on the works of Sir William Temple (1628-1699), in the hand of James Kent, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)